Guide to the Donald Ogden Stewart and Ella Winter Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1915-1975; Series II; 37.42 linear feet (38 boxes)
  - Ella Winter Writings and Related Papers
    - Pamphlets, 1941-1947; undated (Box 24)
    - New Masses, 1941 June 10 (Box 24)
    - Der Bogen, 1947 May (Box 24)
    - "In Fact" newsletters, 1940-1943; 4 (Box 24)
    - "Hollywood Now" newsletters, 1937-1939 (Box 24)
    - "Duplicates of Magazine Articles", 1898-1910; undated (Box 24)
    - "Soviet Miracle Men," published version, Coronet, 1945 June (Box 24)
    - Soviet Russia Today, 1939 June (Box 24)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, "Thirty-Threed: A Tale of the Mexican Border Today," published version, Everybody's Magazine, 1916-1917; undated (Box 24)
    - The Clipper, 1941 January (Box 24)
    - McClure's Magazine, 1915 July (Box 24)
    - Steffens, Lincoln, "The Battle of Celayo," printed version, Collier's, 1921-1922 (Box 24)
    - Direction, 1940 March-April (Box 24)
    - Time, 1944 November 27 (Box 24)
    - The Saturday Review of Literature, 1940 Sep 21 (Box 24)
    - "Speaking of Peace" report, 1949 (Box 24)
    - "Minutes and Proceedings of the First Pacific Coast Congress against War and Fascism", 1935 April 28 (Box 24)
    - Notes, undated; 2 (Box 24)
    - Clippings, circa 1928-1946; undated; 3 folders (Box 24)
    - The Carmel Cymbal, circa 1932-1942; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - The Carmelite, circa 1928-1932; 13 folders (Box 25)
    - The Daily Carmelite, 1931 (Box 25)
    - The Carmel Pine Cone, 1932-1934 (Box 25)
    - Study guides, 1933; 1948 (Box 25)
    - The Christian Register: Unitarian, 1944 January-1946 January (Box 25)
    - New Times, 1947 November 7 (Box 25)
    - Free World, 1941 October (Box 25)
    - Wertheimer, F.I., M.D. "The Recent Development of Metapsychology.", 1924 (Box 25)
    - Creative Writing, 1939 October (Box 25)
    - "Eyewitness: Peekskill U.S.A." report, 1949 October (Box 25)
    - The New Republic, 1940 June 17 (Box 25)
    - Now and Then, 1930 (Box 25)
    - Das Kunstwerk, 1946-1947 (Box 25)
    - "The Truth About the Book the Nazis Like" report, 1945 (Box 25)
    - Mondrian, Piet. "Plastic Art and Pure Plastic Art.", 1945 (Box 25)
    - VVV, 1944 February (Box 25)
    - "Is Stalin Grooming a 'Free Germany' Government?" press release, 1945 (Box 25)
    - The New Argosy, 1945 May (Box 25)
    - Survey Graphic, 1931 October (Box 25)
    - New Masses, 1941-1942; 4 (Box 25)
    - Writings about Hollywood, 1937-1939; undated (Box 26)
    - Writings about Eastern Europe, 1948; undated (Box 26)
    - "Ella Winter: Speeches, radio talks, writings", undated (Box 26)
    - "E.W./D.O.S., Sr.", 1939-1949; undated (Box 26)
    - "My articles/Winter", 1944-1945; undated (Box 26)
    - "Children", 1944; undated (Box 26)
    - "Discipline of Children", 1943-1944; undated (Box 26)
    - "Sutzkever", 1943; undated (Box 26)
    - "Theater", 1944; undated (Box 26)
    - "Trade union", 1944 (Box 26)
    - "Anti-fascist women", 1944; undated (Box 26)
    - "Radio scripts", undated (Box 26)
    - "Writing", undated (Box 26)
    - "Is Stalin Grooming a 'Free Germany' Government?" press release, 1945 (Box 26)
    - "Published articles / Duplicates", undated (Box 26)
    - Pages of a play, undated (Box 26)
    - "General Material for Novel", undated (Box 26)
    - Essays by Ella Winter, undated (Box 26)
    - "Book/copied", undated (Box 26)
    - "Royal Road/copied", undated (Box 26)
    - "Hungary", 1948; undated (Box 26)
    - "Czech material", 1947-1948; undated (Box 26)
    - "Czechoslovakia", undated (Box 26)
    - "The Mentality of Apes" by W. Koehler, undated (Box 26)
    - Folder "Private: Letters of Comment & Reviews of 'Red Virtue'", 1933; undated (Box 26)
    - "On Prohibition of the Atomic Weapon and Reduction of the Armaments of the Five Great Powers by One-Third" by A.Y. Vyshinsky, 1948 October 13 (Box 26)
    - "Confessions of a Congress Delegate" by Feliks Topolski, 1949 (Box 26)
    - Speeches by various speakers, 1948 September 8 (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous notes and writings, 1948; undated (Box 26)
    - Clippings, 1948-1949; undated; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - "Footprints of the Trojan Horse" report, 1940 (Box 27)
    - The Rural Worker, 1936 July (Box 27)
    - The Saturday Review of Literature, 1931 September 12 (Box 27)
    - The New Republic, 1932-1937 (Box 27)
    - The Manchester Guardian Weekly, 1939 Feb 17 (Box 27)
    - "Northern California Political Prisoners Bulletin" newsletter, 1933-1934 (Box 27)
    - National Issues, 1939 March (Box 27)
    - The Nation, 1931; 1941 (Box 27)
    - "Proceedings Third U.S. Congress against War and Fascism" report, 1936 February (Box 27)
    - The Clare Market Review, 1931 Summer (Box 27)
    - "Red Material/misc.", 1936; undated (Box 27)
    - Essays about Eastern Europe, 1939; undated (Box 27)
    - Photograph of first page of "The Making of a Fighter" by Lincoln Steffens, 1907 August (Box 27)
    - Scrapbook "Articles by Ella Winter", 1925-1927 (Box 27)
    - Scrapbook of clippings, 1933; undated (Box 27)
    - Clippings, 1923-1944; undated; 19 folders (Box 27)
    - The Open Forum, 1933-1939 (Box 27)
    - Diaries, address books and postcards, 1912-1921; 3 (Box 27)
    - "Schools/Universities/ Teachers' Union", 1935-1936; undated (Box 28)
    - "Disaster Ordinance", undated (Box 28)
    - "San Diego Labor Council", 1935; undated (Box 28)
    - "Stuff on America", 1927-1928; undated (Box 28)
    - "Article", 1938; undated (Box 28)
    - "Things to read", 1942; undated (Box 28)
    - "The Dilemmas of Today's Political Life", 1930; undated (Box 28)
    - "Wealth on the Waterfront", 1941; undated (Box 28)
    - "Mooney", 1935; undated (Box 28)
    - "Answers to attacks", 1938; undated (Box 28)
    - "Rural Observer", 1932-1940; undated (Box 28)
    - "Hollywood/VJ", 1934; undated (Box 28)
    - "Red-baiting--Culture" (empty), undated (Box 28)
    - "Capitalist Press Clippings", undated (Box 28)
    - "G. of S.F." empty, undated (Box 28)
    - "Communism", undated (Box 28)
    - "Red-baiting--Sinclair", undated (Box 28)
    - "Red-baiting Outside California" (empty), undated (Box 28)
    - "Hunger March", undated (Box 28)
    - "Union News", 1935-1936 (Box 28)
    - "Vigilantes", undated (Box 28)
    - "Capitalists on Communists", 1935 (Box 28)
    - "'Economic Notes'", 1935-1936 (Box 28)
    - "My Lecture Material" (empty), undated (Box 28)
    - "Protests", 1933 August 14 (Box 28)
    - "Film Material for Book", undated (Box 28)
    - "Screen Actors Guild", 1939; undated (Box 28)
    - "China", undated (Box 28)
    - Empty manila envelope, undated (Box 28)
    - "Yugo", 1948; undated (Box 28)
    - "EW/Book on Central Europe", 1947; undated (Box 28)
    - "Krav", 1949; undated (Box 28)
    - Clippings, 1938-1949; undated; 5 folders (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous notes and writings, undated (Box 28)
    - "Scottsboro", 1934; undated (Box 29)
    - "Bills", 1939; undated (Box 29)
    - "Agriculture", 1936; undated (Box 29)
    - Migratory Labor Camp reports, 1936 (Box 29)
    - "Labor Strikes", 1933; undated (Box 29)
    - "Material for articles", 1934; undated (Box 29)
    - "Film notes/My book", 1939; undated (Box 29)
    - "Communism", 1935-1936; undated (Box 29)
    - "Clippings to read", 1939-1940; undated (Box 29)
    - "The Polish and Czechoslovakian Economies in Transformation", undated (Box 29)
    - Notecards, undated (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous notes and writings, 1934; undated; 9 folders (Box 29)
    - Clippings, 1918-1942; undated; 14 folders (Box 29)
    - Poems, undated (Box 29)
    - U.S. Week, 1941-1942; 15 (Box 30)
    - Close Up, 1929 August (Box 30)
    - The Harvard Advocate, 1938 June (Box 30)
    - "Migratory Labor in California" report, 1936 July 11 (Box 30)
    - "Soviet Art in Wartime" report, 1943 February (Box 30)
    - "One Year of Soviet Struggle against German Invasion" report, 1942 (Box 30)
    - "All Out! How Democracy Will Defend America" by Samuel Grafton, 1940 (Box 30)
    - Modern American Society preliminary edition of book, 1940 (Box 30)
    - Clippings, 1932-1939; undated; 3 folders (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1931; undated (Box 30)
    - "Variety" newsletter, 1938-1939; 6 (Box 31)
    - "The Hollywood Reporter" newsletter, 1938-1940; 8 (Box 31)
    - Screen Writers Guild arbitrations with the National Labor Relations Board, 1938-1939 (Box 31)
    - Pamphlets, 1928-1933; undated; 3 folders (Box 31)
    - The Malvern Gazette, 1929; 2 (Box 31)
    - California Life, 1927 May 15 (Box 31)
    - Editor & Publisher, 1934; 2 (Box 31)
    - Nation's Business, 1935 March (Box 31)
    - Writings about the Pacific Coast Longshoremen's Strike, 1934 (Box 31)
    - Hollywood Now, 1938-1940; 5 (Box 31)
    - The Hollywood Tribune, 1939 (Box 31)
    - "Art-Music", 1938-1939; undated (Box 31)
    - Clippings, 1927-1940; undated; 5 folders (Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1939; undated (Box 31)
    - Clippings, 1917-1948; undated; 22 folders (Box 32)
    - Aperitif, 1935 Febuary (Box 32)
    - The Town Crier, 1934 October 11 (Box 32)
    - Town & Country, 1941 September (Box 32)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1936 November (Box 32)
    - Pamphlets, 1933-1939; undated; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, newsletters, and writings, 1931-1940; undated; 5 folders (Box 32)
    - "The Hollywood Reporter" and "Variety" newsletters, 1940 (Box 32)
    - Clippings, 1936; 9 (Box 33)
    - Pamphlets, 1942-1947; undated; 4 folders (Box 33)
    - German publications, 1925-1947; 3 (Box 33)
    - Story, 1937 November (Box 33)
    - The Modern Quarterly, 1930-1932; 2 (Box 33)
    - Hollywood Spectator, 1938 November 26 (Box 33)
    - New Theatre, 1935-1936; 4 (Box 34)
    - "New Theatre and Film", 1937 March (Box 34)
    - Hollywood Now, 1937-1940; 2 (Box 34)
    - Nash's Pall Mall Magazine, 1930 November (Box 34)
    - Navy magazines, 1918, 1937 (Box 34)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1937 March (Box 34)
    - "The Role of the Individual in History" by George Plekhanov, 1940 (Box 34)
    - Clippings, 1914-1942; undated; 15 folders (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous notes and writings, 1936; undated; 6 folders (Box 34)
    - Pamphlets, 1933; undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Russian newspapers, 1931; 2 (Box 34)
    - Russian publications, 1928-1931; undated; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - "Psychiatry and Crime in Russia", undated (Box 34)
    - "The Story of a Progressive Educational Enterprise" report, 1931 (Box 34)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, 1933-1937; undated (Box 34)
    - Notes and clippings, 1936; 1941; undated (Box 35)
    - Notes and articles, 1939; undated (Box 35)
    - Newspaper clippings and other printed material, 1931-1938; 2 (Box 35)
    - Notes and other papers, 1936; undated (Box 35)
    - "Carmel," business papers, 1951-1963 (Box 35)
    - "Italy and France", 1944; 1948 (Box 35)
    - "Hollywood", 1948; 1950 (Box 35)
    - "Yugoslavia", 1947-1948 (Box 35)
    - "Logic of Anti-Soviet Argument", circa 1947 (Box 35)
    - Germany, 1947; 2 (Box 35)
    - Miscellaneous printed and notes, 1949-1950 (Box 35)
    - "Czechoslovakia. Book: European Diary", 1948 (Box 35)
    - Two notebooks, 1911-1912 (Box 35)
    - Steffens, Lincoln: Tales of the Quarters, typescript, 1906 (Box 35)
    - "Paris Peace Conference. E. W. Notes", 1948-1949; 2 (Box 35)
    - "USSR", 1947; undated (Box 35)
    - "Clippings. US Drops Iron Curtain on Scientists", 1941-1946 (Box 35)
    - Art News, 1940-1941; 13 (Box 36)
    - The International Studio, 1921 February (Box 36)
    - The Magazine Antiques, 1941 December (Box 36)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1942 February (Box 36)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., auction catalogue, 1942 April (Box 36)
    - California. State Department of Institutions. Aaron J. Rosanoff, M. D., Director. Report of His Excellency, Culbert L. Olson Governor, 1939 January 30 (Box 36)
    - Scribner's Magazine, 1934 January (Box 36)
    - Catalogues and pamphlets, 1946-1950; 2 (Box 36)
    - Printed material: Russian, 1931; 1944; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - California Eagle, 1950 August 18 (Box 36)
    - New Masses, 1934 July 24 (Box 36)
    - Asia, 1932 March (Box 36)
    - Soviet Russia Today, 1935 November (Box 36)
    - New Times, 1949 May 4 (Box 36)
    - Facts on the Blacklist in Radio and Television, undated (Box 36)
    - Freies Deutschland, 1943 March (Box 36)
    - Printed material: miscellaneous, 1889-1945; 4 (Box 36)
    - Book jackets, undated (Box 36)
    - Clippings, 1915-1948; 10 (Box 36)
    - Rukeyser, Muriel. The Soul and Body of John Brown, typescript, signed by the author, 1940 February (Box 36)
    - "Short Stories", undated (Box 37)
    - "Joliot", 1949 (Box 37)
    - "Bow Lectures. Economic Theory", 1922 (Box 37)
    - Unidentified typescript, undated (Box 37)
    - "Fact. My Book on Central Europe", 1949 (Box 37)
    - Miscellaneous writings by Ella Winter, 1922; 1948; undated; 13 folders (Box 37)
    - Empty folders, undated (Box 37)
    - Lincoln Steffens, undated (Box 37)
    - "Various Articles", 1940-1941 (Box 38)
    - "Ella Winter", 1930-1937 (Box 38)
    - "Ella Winter. Vancouver Lecture," clippings, 1931 (Box 38)
    - International Press Correspondence, 1937 (Box 38)
    - Soviet Union Review, 1931 (Box 38)
    - Research Bulletin on the Soviet Union, 1937 (Box 38)
    - Clippings, 1931 (Box 38)
    - "On Man's Eternal Consciousness:" typescript, undated (Box 38)
    - "Barrow Dunham MS:" typescript, undated (Box 38)
    - The Carmelite, 1928; 6 (Box 38)
    - Printed material: miscellaneous, 1920-1939; 6 (Box 38)
    - "Wroclaw. Paris", 1948-1949 (Box 39)
    - "Wroclaw", 1948 (Box 39)
    - "John Fischer", 1947 (Box 39)
    - Printed material relating to Hungary, 1948-1949 (Box 39)
    - "Women (Jessica)...", undated (Box 39)
    - "Trade Schools. Young Workers", 1944 (Box 39)
    - Fragments, typescript, undated (Box 39)
    - Clippings, 1923-1924 (Box 39)
    - "Poland", undated (Box 39)
    - "Rebound" clippings, 1930 (Box 39)
    - Notes, undated (Box 39)
    - "Book reviews", 1949 (Box 39)
    - "Autobiog", 1947; undated (Box 39)
    - "France", 1948 (Box 39)
    - "Abbé Bouller", 1948 November (Box 39)
    - "D[ark] L[egend]", 1941 (Box 39)
    - "Psychology", 1940; undated (Box 39)
    - "American Federation of Teachers", 1919-1941 (Box 39)
    - "Granville Hicks Bulletin", undated (Box 39)
    - "La Follette Committee", 1939-1940 (Box 39)
    - "Darcy", 1941 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1941-1950; undated; 3; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Clippings, 1941-1949; 5 (Box 39)
    - Scrapbook, 1920-1936 (Box 40)
    - "Duplicates of Articles by Ella Winter", 1925-1934 (Box 40)
    - "Articles. Ella Winter", 1922-1927 (Box 40)
    - "Ella Winter. Clippings of articles. Reviews...:", 1931-1933 (Box 40)
    - Physical Culture, 1932 (Box 40)
    - Asia, 1932 (Box 40)
    - Town & Country, 1941 (Box 40)
    - Clippings, 1924-1936; 9 (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous printed material, 1931; 1935 (Box 40)
    - Notes, undated; 2 (Box 40)
    - Printed material, including pamphlets and clippings, 1925-1947; 16 (Box 41)
    - Income tax list, 1925 (Box 41)
    - "Poems", undated (Box 41)
    - Printed material, 1932-1947; 9 (Box 42)
    - "On Soviets", undated (Box 42)
    - "Reds", 1934-1938 (Box 42)
    - "McNamara", 1939-1940 (Box 42)
    - Notes, fragments and printed material, undated; 4 (Box 42)
    - Printed material, including articles and reviews by Ella Winter, 1931-1947; 7 (Box 42)
    - Subject Files (Box 43)
      - A. C. L. U., 1938 (Box 43)
      - A. F. A., undated (Box 43)
      - Americanism in Movies, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Anti-Nazi League, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Anti-Semitism, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Beecroft Case, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Better America Federation, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Block Booking, undated (Box 43)
      - "Blockade", 1938 (Box 43)
      - Book of the Day Shop/Club, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Bridges Case, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Bund, German American, 1938 (Box 43)
      - C. I. O., 1938 (Box 43)
      - California Committee Against No. 1, 1938 (Box 43)
      - California Congress, undated (Box 43)
      - Censorship, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Citizen News (empty folder) (Box 43)
      - Chaplin, Charlie, 1938-1939, 1957-1967 (Box 43)
      - Clippings re: movies, 1937-1938 (Box 43)
      - Committee of 43 (empty folder) (Box 43)
      - Committee of 56, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Czechoslovakia, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Dies, Martin, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Directors (Screen) Guild, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Economic Conditions in Film Colony, undated (Box 43)
      - Federal Theatre Project, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Finance of Movie Industry, 1937-1938 (Box 43)
      - La Follette Case, 1937-1939 (Box 43)
      - Foreign Countries and American Films, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Freedom of the Screen Censorship (empty folder) (Box 43)
      - Germany, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Hollywood, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Hollywood and Politics Edit[orial] Opinion, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Hollywood Tribune, 1939 (Box 43)
      - I. A. T. S. E., 1939 (Box 43)
      - Individuals Progressive Pix, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Interviews, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Japan, 1938 (Box 43)
      - "K" (empty folder), undated (Box 43)
      - League of Women Shoppers, undated (Box 43)
      - McNamara Case, undated (Box 43)
      - Middle Class Reactionary Organizations, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Mooney, Tom, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Motion Picture Artists Committee, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Motion Picture Democratic Committee, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Movies-Individual, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Mussolini, Vittorio, 1937 (Box 43)
      - N. L. R. B., 1937-1938 (Box 43)
      - Neutral Thousands, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Rienstahl, Leni, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Schafer Party, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Screen Writers Guilds, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - Spain in Hollywood, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Strikes, 1938 (Box 43)
      - T. A. C., 1938 (Box 43)
      - Variety (empty folder) (Box 43)
      - Wanger, Walter, undated (Box 43)
      - Warner Brothers, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Western Consumers Union. Movies, 1938-1939 (Box 43)
      - "Western Tide", undated (Box 43)
      - Wolf, Frederick, 1939 (Box 43)
      - Women of the Pacific (empty folder) (Box 43)
      - The Writer hearings before NLRB, 1936 (Box 43)
      - The Writer in Hollywood, 1938 (Box 43)
      - Young Democrats, 1939 (Box 43)
    - Printed material, including clippings, pamphlets and magazines, 1936-1947; 10 (Box 44)
    - Printed material, 1946-1950; 5 (Box 45)
    - "The Nigger Car," typescript, 1947 April 4 (Box 46)
    - "Wait Till You're Married," typescript undated (Box 46)
    - Notebook: Ames Ogden Stewart, undated (Box 46)
    - Marineland Melodrama: typescript, undated (Box 46)
    - Essays: ms., 1915 (Box 46)
    - Clippings, circa 1923-1933; 12 folders (Box 46)
    - Clippings, circa 1923-1933; 6 folders (Box 46)
    - Printed material, 1913-1921; 17 (Box 47)
    - Notebook, circa 1943 (Box 48)
    - Principles of Proposed Agreement Between Screen Writers Guild And Producers, 1939 April 27 (Box 48)
    - Notes, undated; 2 (Box 48)
    - Lectures, 1944, undated; 2 folders (Box 48)
    - Articles on China and research notes, 1958; 3 (Box 48)
      Includes photographs
    - "What America can Teach Europe," lecture notes, 1928 (Box 48)
    - Contract with Modern Age Books for "Hollywood Goes Human", 1939 (Box 48)
    - Outline for arrangement of Ella Winter's papers, undated (Box 48)
    - World War II notes (Box 48)
    - Those Who Mismanage the World: Appeasement Then and Now, typescript (Box 48)
    - "The Chaplin Film Greets the World" drafts A,B,C, typed, corrected, undated; 3 (Box 48)
    - "Nazism in Reverse" typed draft, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 48)
    - Notes on Vincent Van Gogh, undated (Box 48)
    - "Adult Delinquency" typed draft, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 48)
    - "The Audience's the Thing" typed draft, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 48)
    - "When Mussolini Fell" typed draft, carbon, undated (Box 48)
    - "That Question of Post-War Germany" typed draft, carbon, undated (Box 48)
    - "The Scorched Earth Re-born" typed draft, carbon, corrected, undated (Box 48)
    - Submission about Ella Winter for Who's Who in the East, 1952 (Box 48)
    - Notes, 1949, undated (Box 48)
    - Contracts, Agreements, 1931 May 25; 1937 June; 2 folders (Box 48)
  - Printed Material
    - Clippings, Brochures, and Pamphlets
      - Clippings about Donald Ogden Stewart's writings, circa 1922-1941; 27 folders (Box 49)
        Including: Escapade, Father William, Fighting Words, Fine and Dandy, Finn and Hattie, Holiday, Honour Bright, Laughter, Los Angeles, Mr. and Mrs. Haddock in Paris France, Not So Dumb, A Parody Outline of History, Perfect Behavior, Philadelphia Story, Rebound, Tarnished Lady, That Certain Feeling, Witness
      - Clippings and pamphlets by and about Donald Ogden Stewart, 1921-1928; 6 (Box 50)
      - Clippings from magazines and newspapers, 5 (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Charlie Chaplin, 1967, undated (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Ernest Hemingway, sent to Stewart about Lillian Russell's husband, 1925 (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Filbert H. Stewart, Judge, 1864-1893 (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Frederic Wertham and comics, 1946-1963, undated; 3 folders (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Ella Winter and Family, 1936 (Box 50)
      - Clippings about John Hay Whitney wedding, 1930 (Box 50)
      - Clippings about Ames Ogden Stewart, 1926 (Box 50)
      - Unsorted clippings, circa 1912-1940; 11 folders (Box 50)
      - Announcements and flyers, 1909-1922 (Box 51)
      - Periodicals, 1922; 1927; 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Programs, 1912-1919 (Box 51)
      - Pamphlets, reprints, and brochures (Box 51)
      - Various printed material, 1918-1951; 5 (Box 51)
    - Newspapers and Magazines
      - The Carmel Pine Cone, 1934 February 16
      - The Carmel Pine Cone, 1936 May 22; 1936 June 12-19; 1934 September 7
      - The Carmel Pine Cone, 1931 May 22; 1934 August 10-31; 1936 May 22; 1934 January 26; 1935 May 24
      - Carmel Sun, 1933 September 21
      - The Carmelite, 1932 February 4
      - The Californian, 1936 June 25
      - Collier's, 1921 January 15; 1939 March 4
      - Delineator, 1928 March, 1929 October
      - The Exonian, 1910-1912
      - Hollywood Spectator, 1939 April 15
      - The Hollywood Tribune, 1939 September 11, 18; 1939 August 14; 1939 May 19
      - The Hollywood Tribune, 1939 July 10; 1939 July 3; 1939 June 23
      - The Hollywood Tribune [2 copies], 1939 June 23
      - The Hollywood Tribune [11 copies], 1939 September 18
      - The Hollywood Tribune, 1939 June 2-16
      - The Pacific Rural Press, 1934 September 15
      - Pictorial Review, 1930 April
      - The Wasp, 1932 June 11
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 27
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 21-25
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 21; October 22; 1936 July 27
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 21
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 17-20
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 10-20
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 5-23; 1927 December 16; 1933 November 14-17
      - Newspapers, 1933 November 2-11; 1933 October 12-28
      - Newspapers, 1933 October 13-19; 1936 June 4-29; 1936 May 11
      - Newspapers, 1936 May 7-18; 1936 April 6-27; 1936 Feb 10-24; 1936 March 16
      - Newspapers, 1934 May 20; 1936 May 11-25; 1936 June 1-22; 1936 August 31
      - Newspapers, 1909 September 15-1910 June 25
      - Newspaper, 1959 June 27
      - French magazine, 1931 December 16
      - Russian Magazines, 1930; 3
  - Writings of Others
    - Barnes, W. H., "The Christmas Chair," typescript, undated (Box 52)
    - Barton, A. H. "Lloyd George Knew My Father: A Tribute" typed draft, corrected, undated (Box 52)
    - Cherkassova, Alexandra, "This Been Accomplished by Soviet People" typescript, undated (Box 52)